Guide to the Steve Nelson Papers ALBA.008
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series VI: Subject Files
  - International Brigade: Soviet Union, 1969, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - International Brigade: Yugoslavia, undated, 1967-1976 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Israel: Statement on Israel and Middle East Peace, 1973 (?) (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Jackson, Gabriel: Essays on Spanish Politics (typescripts), ca.1982 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Joint Anti-Fascist Refugee Committee: Spanish Refugee Appeal, 1952 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Kochi, Paul: "Imin no Aiwa" (An Immigrant's Sorrowful Tale), 1978 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Malraux-Hemingway: "Embattled Spain" Symposium (Boston College): Program, notes, and papers, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Marion, George: "Defense of Madrid" (typescript), 1937 (?) (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Marzani, Carl: "Orwell, Spain and 1992" (typescript & notes), undated (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Marzani, Carl: "Orwell, Spain & the Cold War," preface by Nelson (typescript draft & notes), 1980-1987 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Marzani, Carl: "Orwell, Spain & the Cold War," (typescript draft & notes), folder 1, 1980-1987 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Marzani, Carl: "Orwell, Spain & the Cold War," (typescript draft & notes), folder 2, 1980-1987 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Marzani, Carl: "Orwell, Spain & the Cold War," (typescript draft & notes), folder 1, 1980-1987 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Marzani, Carl: "The Promise of Euro-communism" (partial typescript), ca.1980 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Medina, Harold R., 1954 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Morning Freiheit: Clippings, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Nelson, Steve: Clippings, 1969-1988 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Nelson, Steve: Hawaii Trip, 1987-1990 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Nelson, Steve: Interview in Salmagundi conducted by Donald Miller: drafts & correspondence, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Nelson, Steve: "Nelson and the Spanish Civil War" (typescript article), author unidentified, ca.1976 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Nelson, Steve: "Oppenheimer" (PBS TV series) Dispute, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Nelson, Steve: Poetry Tributes, 1943-1975 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Nelson, Steve: Transcription of oral history conducted by Dennis Pearl, undated (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Nelson, Steve: Transcription of oral history related to Sedition Trial, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - New Movement, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - New Masses: Promotional Material, 1951-1953 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - North, Joseph: "For Valor in Battle" (VALB pamphlet supporting Smith Act defendants), 1952 (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Ohio Committee for the Smith Act Defendants: Dave and Frieda Katz, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - Onda, Andrew: Sedition Trial, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - Ost, Milton: Poetry, undated (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - Ottanelli, Fraser: Popular Front essays, 1983, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 43)
  - Philippines: U.S. Policy, 1973-1984 (Box 10, Folder 44)
  - Quin, Mike: "Not Valid for Travel In Spain, " essay (typescript), undated (Box 10, Folder 45)
  - Reagan, Ronald: remarks Critical of VALB, 1984-1985 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Rolfe, Edwin: Letter to Random House (photocopy), undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Shields, Art: "Pittsburgh: Peace on Trial" (pamphlet), 1951 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Shirai, Jack: "The Life & Death of a Japanese Volunteer in the Spanish Civil War," (pamphlet) by Yo Kawanari, undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Slovo, Joe: "Has Socialism Failed?" (essay), with critique by Nelson, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Smorodin, Ted: Spanish Civil War Curriculum for High School Students, undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Sobell, Morton, 1955 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Soviet Union: 20th Anniversary Celebration, Wilkes-Barre, PA: Souvenir Program (picture of Nelson on the cover), Nov 1937 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Spain: Asociacion de Ex-Presos y Represaliados (Association of Ex-Political Prisoners), 1983 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Spain: Guernica, undated, 1984-1987 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Spain: Politics, 1970-1982 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Spain: Politics: Carabanchel 10, 1973-1975 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Spain: Politics: Carabanchel 10: Statements of Protest, 1973-1974 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Spain: Politics: Clippings, 1975-1983 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Spain: Politics: Protests against Franco, ca.1974 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Spain: U.S. Foreign Relations, 1971-1982 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Spain: Workers' Commissions of Spain, ca.1975 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Spanish Civil War: Clippings, undated, 1937-1941 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Spanish Civil War: Clippings: Veterans, 1975-1984 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Spanish Civil War: Film Projects & Proposals, undated, 1971-1975 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Spanish Civil War: Poetry, undated, 1933, 1978-1986 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Spanish Civil War: Symposia & Curricula, undated, 1981-1988 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Spanish Communist Party (Partido Comunista de Espana), 1977-1978 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Spanish Refugee Aid, Inc., undated, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - "Steve Nelson: A Tribute by 14 Authors" (pamphlet), 1952 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Tivin, Isadore & Stephan Zak: "Spain Revisited: Canadian Style", 1979 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Trepper, Leopold, 1972-1973 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Truman and the Red Scare (clipping), ca.1950 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Union de Excombatientes de la Guerra de Espana, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Vidali, Vittorio, 1982-1983 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Vietnam, 1977-1985 (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Viewpoint: correspondence; typescript drafts; serials, 1977-1980 (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Vogel, Sidney: "War Medicine" (essay on medical conditions and practice in Spain), ca.1937 (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - Watson, William: "Twenty-Five Years of Military Involvement in Spain, 1951-1975" (typescript) (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - Watt, George: Writings (2 essays), 1983, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - Wayne State University: Spanish Civil War Scholarship Fund, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 36)
  - Williamson et al. v. United States, 1950 (Box 11, Folder 37)
  - Wyden, Peter: Materials related to The Passionate War, 1980-1983 (Box 11, Folder 38)